<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Geek w/ god complex</title>
    <link>http://blog.nicro.land/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Geek w/ god complex</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 14:39:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.nicro.land/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Remapping zoom slider on Microsoft Ergonomic Keyboard</title>
      <link>http://blog.nicro.land/p1487/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 14:39:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nicro.land/p1487/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m a big fan of Microsoft&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;Natural Ergonomic Keyboard 4000&amp;#8221;. I&amp;#8217;m just not a fan of it&amp;#8217;s name, it&amp;#8217;s a mouthful! (How about for future reference we just call it the Ergo?)
&amp;nbsp;
The Ergo&amp;#8217;s great for typing on and also has a selection of feature keys that you can key-map to. Depending on your distro/desktop environment, you can map keys for all sorts of reasons: to replace caps lock with ctrl, control your music player, to run scripts, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Markdown notes server</title>
      <link>http://blog.nicro.land/p992/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 08:35:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nicro.land/p992/</guid>
      <description>I keep a lot of notes&amp;#8230;
Writing notes Any time I&amp;#8217;m researching anything computing related, whether it&amp;#8217;s for work or in my spare time, I keep a log of my &amp;#8220;stream of conciousness&amp;#8221;. This includes thoughts like &amp;#8220;I think this is because&amp;#8230;&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;I wonder if this is related to&amp;#8230;&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;What the fuck is&amp;#8230;?&amp;#8221;.
This is great when I&amp;#8217;ve spent a lot of time learning something new and I can look back over them once a week to reinforce the stuff I&amp;#8217;ve covered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Security Risks: GUIs &#43; Xorg</title>
      <link>http://blog.nicro.land/p496/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2016 11:39:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nicro.land/p496/</guid>
      <description>Recently I wrote a post where I was running a GUI application in a docker container. I did so because I couldn&amp;#8217;t be confident of the software&amp;#8217;s origins and thought it&amp;#8217;d be best not to take any chances. What other potential exploits does this leave one vulnerable to and how can one best protect themselves?
But isn&amp;#8217;t everything running in Docker secure? First things first, let&amp;#8217;s talk about what kind of security assurances docker tries to provide and under what circumstances those assurances would be considered null and void.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nested decorator functions in Python</title>
      <link>http://blog.nicro.land/p555/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 23:32:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nicro.land/p555/</guid>
      <description>When I was at PyConIE last October I was talking with an old friend about Python&amp;#8217;s decorator functions.
He lamented how you need to google around for tutorials any time you wanted to write a parametrised decorator because it can be so confusing. I told him that there was a way to do it by nesting decorator functions which is much simpler than implementing them using classes (which seems to be the widely known about way).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running QtCreator in Docker</title>
      <link>http://blog.nicro.land/p87/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2015 19:53:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nicro.land/p87/</guid>
      <description>Update: I wrote a follow up post detailing potential security risks of running GUIs in containers, check it out here.
The first thing I ever tried installing from source was Qt. For those who don&amp;#8217;t know, Qt is a cross platform framework for writing GUI applications.
That was then&amp;#8230; I was in college, I had a macbook at the time and I was toying around with writing GUIs with Python/Tkinter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golang Ramblings from a Python Dev</title>
      <link>http://blog.nicro.land/p61/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2015 07:28:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nicro.land/p61/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been spending time lately learning Go and I thought I&amp;#8217;d throw some of my thoughts down here. As the title implies my experience is mostly in Python so expect lots of apples to oranges comparisons!

Tooling I guess the first thing that jumps out is the quality of the tooling, I&amp;#8217;ve only had a chance to play around with a few of the CLI&amp;#8217;s features but already I&amp;#8217;m impressed with how simple it makes some day to day things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I’m back!</title>
      <link>http://blog.nicro.land/p58/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2015 14:36:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nicro.land/p58/</guid>
      <description>I know that it&amp;#8217;s been a while since I wrote a post! I haven&amp;#8217;t been keeping up with my own goal to write something new at least every week.
At first this was because I was on holidays and internet access was spotty at best. More recently I&amp;#8217;ve been very busy at work and not had as much time for reflection. I wanted to call this out here to keep myself honest and to make a fresh commitment!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Notes – 26/7/15</title>
      <link>http://blog.nicro.land/p50/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 12:06:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nicro.land/p50/</guid>
      <description>Setup.py and rpm.spec:
So recently at work I needed to package a tool we wrote at work. The tool was written in Python (big surprise) and it was designed to be run as a daemon so it had an init-script.
Most Python tools are packaged by writing a `setup.py` script. There are actually a number of tools you can use (I&amp;#8217;ve used distutils and setuptools in the past) and there&amp;#8217;s a bit of a confusing history regarding which tool is recommended.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Notes – 18/7/15</title>
      <link>http://blog.nicro.land/p10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 10:18:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nicro.land/p10/</guid>
      <description>This is the first post in a series that I&amp;#8217;ll (hopefully) send out every week. It&amp;#8217;ll cover the problems I have during the week as well as how I overcome those issues.
Hopefully this will be of some use to people out there, leave me a comment if you find any of this useful!
Docker machine + docker compose
https://raw.githubusercontent.com/docker/machine/master/docs/img/logo.png
So I&amp;#8217;ve been playing around with docker-machine while working on a pet project of mine: daftpunk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello world!</title>
      <link>http://blog.nicro.land/p7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 21:46:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.nicro.land/p7/</guid>
      <description>Why I started this blog
I&amp;#8217;m not very good at writing about my experiences, I prefer to just talk. In fact I could ramble on about my own thing all night, constantly meandering and exploring tangents as I go.
I&amp;#8217;ve decided that I should put more of an effort into collecting my thoughts in blog form so that I can focus them. At the very least I hope this will make me a better developer but maybe I&amp;#8217;ll help others who run into the same stumbling blocks on their own journey.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>